Guide to the Darlene Wone Papers TAM.643
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Darlene Wone Papers
1968-1985
TAM.643
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet in two manuscript boxes and one oversize folder
The materials in this collection consist of organizational documents, internal notes, flyers, leaflets, publicity, and visual materials that appear to have been collected by Darlene Wone (also known as Mei Oye Soohoo), in the course of her years an activist in the Asian American and Asian/Pacific American women's movement, as well as the Asian/Pacific American Movement more generally. The large variety and number of names of organizations and projects included in this small collection reflects the birth and explosive growth of ethnic political and cultural organizations that took place in the United States during the 1970s and 1980s.
Arrangement
Folders are in one series, arranged by title in alphabetical order.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Appraisal note
Duplicates have been separated from this collection.
Historical/Biographical Note
From approximately the middle 1970s through the late 1980s, Darlene Wone was an activist in the Asian American and Asian/Pacific American women's movement, as well as the Asian/Pacific American Movement more generally. These movements, arising as part of the ferment of the broader civil rights and women's movements of the 1960s and 1970s in the United States, were formed to struggle against racial and sexual steriotypes and discrimination against Asian Americans and Asian/Pacific Islander Americans. Wone (also known as Mei Oye, and Mei Oye Soo Hoo in the 1970s and 1980s), a Brooklyn-born Chinese American and a college graduate, worked in the television broadcast industry and public relations. Memberships she held and positions she served in organizations arising from these movements included a stint as editor for In Touch, the newsletter of the New York City-based feminist Asian Women United, public relations coordinator for the Coalition of Asian/Pacific American Associations, member of the official delegation to the National Network of Asian and Pacific Women to the First National Asian/Pacific American Women's Conference for Educational Equity, and member of a fundraising committee for the New York Asian/Pacific American Women's Network.
Scope and Content Note
The materials in this collection consist of organizational documents, internal notes, flyers, leaflets, publicity, and visual materials that appear to have been collected by Darlene Wone in the course of her activities in the Asian/Pacific American women's movement and the Asian/Pacific American movement that reflect the breadth of her interest in these movements, as well as in feminism and civil rights more generally. What is more, the sheer variety and large number of names of organizations and projects represented in this small collection alone also reflects the rich flowering of ethnic political and cultural organizations that took place in the United States during the 1970s and 1980s.
Related Archival Materials
Asian Women United Records and Photographs. TAM 320. Asian Women United Oral History Collection. OH 074. Asian CineVision Records. TAM 416.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
These materials were collected by Darlene Wone and sent by her to Laura Chen-Schulz, Deputy Director of New York University's Asian/Pacific/American Institute, in November of 2013. Chen-Schulz then donated the papers to the Tamiment Library on Wone's behalf. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.002
Asian CineVision (Organization).; Asian Women United.; Chen-Schulz, Laura; Wone, Darlene; Asian American women.; Asian Americans |x Civil rights.; Asian Americans |x Economic conditions.; Asian Americans |x Employment.; Asian Americans |x Social conditions.
- 1981 Asian American Media and Humanities Conference (Box 1)
- Asian CineVision, 1981-1985; undated (Box 1)
- Asian/Pacific American Heritage Festival, 1980-1986 (Box 1)
- Asian/Pacific American Heritage Week, 1979, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
- Asian Pacific Women Employment Project, circa 1980 (Box 1)
- Asian/Pacific Women's Network, 1980, 1983, undated (Box 1)
- Asian/Pacific Women's Task Force on Educational Equity - Northeast Region, 1981 (Box 1)
- Asian Women United, 1981-1985, 2004 (Box 1)
- Coalition of Asian American Professional Women, 1980-1981, 1984 (Box 1)
- Coalition of Asian/Pacific American Associations, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
- First Convention of Asian Indians in North America, 1980 (Box 1)
- First National Asian/Pacific American Women's Conference for Educational Equity (Conference Packet), 1980 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Asian/Pacific American Arts Organizations, circa 1980s, 1998 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Asian/Pacific American Political, Professional, and Educational Organizations, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Non-Asian/Pacific American Feminist and Civil Rights Organizations and Government Entities, 1980-1982; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Feminist and Civil Rights Organizations and Government Entities, 1974, 1976, 1980-1981; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Publications, Clippings, and Documents Re Asian/Pacific Americans, 1976, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
- National Asian American Telecommunication Association, 1982
- National Network of Asian and Pacific Women, 1980-1982, 1984 (Box 2)
- National Network of Asian and Pacific Women - 1982 Biennial Convention Packet (Box 2)
- New York Asian/Pacific Women's Conference - March 1980 (Box 2)
- New York Asian/Pacific Women's Conference - June - August 1980 (Box 2)
- New York Asian/Pacific Women's Network, 1981 (Box 2)
- Organization of Chinese American Women (Metropolitan Washington Area), 1980-1981 (Box 2)
- Organization of Pan Asian American Women, 1980-1983, undated (Box 2)
- Pacific and Asian Women Bay Area Coalition (PAAWBAC), 1980-1981, undated (Box 2)
- Photograph (group photograph of unidentified women, probably at a meeting), circa 1980s (Box 2)
- Political Buttons, 1977, 1987 (Box 2)
- Visual Communications (Asian American media organization), circa 1980s
- Oversized Materials, 1967, 1982 (Box MSXO002)